Douglas Borgstedt Papers
Douglas Borgstedt Papers
1964-1974
Borgstedt, Douglas, 1911-
7 linear ft.
Papers of the American editorial cartoonist. Cartoons from the evening and Sunday Philadelphia Bulletin, distributed by King Features Syndicate, on such topics as Philadelphia, Asia, Vietnam, civil rights, terrorism, the Supersonic Transport, and youth. Also one item of correspondence.
148859
Biographical History
Douglas Borgstedt was an American editorial cartoonist.
Scope and Contents of the Collection
The Douglas Borgstedt Papers comprise 2 series: Correspondence and Cartoons.
Correspondence contains just one folder, holding photocopies of two letters from the Nixon White House, 1971.
Cartoons constitute the bulk of the collection. These are political cartoons originally drawn for the Philadelphia Bulletin, and syndicated with King Features Syndicate, Inc. The cartoons span the years 1964 to 1974, most of them falling in the years 1968 through 1973. The cartoons are subdivided by topic, and then chronologically arranged within each topic.
Related Material
has collections of over one hundred cartoonists. Please refer to for a complete listing.
Subject and Genre Headings
Art -- Cartoonists; Borgstedt, Douglas, 1911- Archives.; King Features Syndicate.; Evening and Sunday Bulletin (Philadelphia, Pa.).; American wit and humor, Pictorial.; Caricatures and cartoons, United States.; Cartoonists, United States.; Editorial cartoons, Pennsylvania, Philadelphia.; Editorial cartoons, United States.; Philadelphia (Pa.), Politics and government, Caricatures and cartoons.; United States, Politics and government, 1963-1969, Caricatures and cartoons.; United States, Politics and government, 1969-1974, Caricatures and cartoons.; Cartoons (humorous images); Editorial cartoons.; Cartoonists.
Access Restrictions
The majority of our archival and manuscript collections are housed offsite and require advanced notice for retrieval. Researchers are encouraged to contact us in advance concerning the collection material they wish to access for their research.
Acquisition Information
Gift of Mr. Borgstedt, 1967-1974.
Inventory
- Correspondence
  - Nixon White House, 1971; 2 photocopied letters (Box 1)
- Cartoons
  - Philadelphia
    - Crime (Box 1)
    - Local finances (Box 1)
    - Local politics (Box 1)
    - Miscellaneous issues (Box 1)
  - Africa
    - Biafra at war with Nigeria (Box 1)
    - Rhodesia and white supremacy (Box 1)
    - Diplomacy (Box 1)
  - Canada (Box 1)
  - Communist countries
    - China - Mao Tse Tung (Box 1)
    - Czechoslovakia - invaded by Russian tanks (Box 1)
    - Eastern Europe (Box 1)
    - Soviet Union
      - Politics and sports (Box 1)
      - Repression (Box 1)
      - Russia and Red China (Box 1)
      - Russia vs. America (Box 1)
  - Europe
    - France, Charles de Gaulle, Pompidou (Box 1)
    - Germany (Box 1)
    - Great Britain (Box 2)
    - North Atlantic Treaty Organization (NATO) (Box 2)
    - Northern Ireland, strife, Catholic vs. Protestant (Box 2)
    - Spain, Franco's dictatorship (Box 2)
  - Latin America
    - Chile, Allende's Marxist government (Box 2)
    - Cuba, Castro's Communism (Box 2)
    - General (Box 2)
  - Mid-East
    - Arab-Israeli relations (Box 2)
    - Arab oil (Box 2)
    - Diplomatic efforts (Box 2)
    - Egypt - Nasser (Box 2)
    - Terrorism (Box 2)
  - Global
    - New Year's strife (Box 2)
    - Overpopulation (Box 2)
    - United Nations, U Thant (Box 2)
    - U.S. image (Box 2)
  - Congress
    - Abuses, Bobby Baker and Adam Clayton Powell (Box 2)
    - Congress vs. Nixon (Box 2)
    - Congress vs. the Pentagon (Box 2)
    - Senator William Fulbright, influencing foreign affairs (Box 2)
    - Legislation (Box 3)
    - Politics (Box 3)
    - Reform (Box 3)
    - Senator Hugh Scott (Box 3)
  - Courts
    - Chicago Seven (Box 3)
    - Freedom of the press (Box 3)
    - Nixon's appointments and Congressional veto (Box 3)
    - Politics (Box 3)
    - James Earl Ray and Sirhan Sirhan, assassins (Box 3)
    - Youth (Box 3)
  - Presidential administration
    - Lyndon Johnson (Box 3)
    - Richard Nixon
      - General, 3 folders (Box 3)
      - Spiro Agnew, battles with the press, resignation (Box 3)
      - Gerald Ford, apopintment as Vice President (Box 3)
      - Henry Kissinger, Secretary of State (Box 3)
      - Watergate scandal (Box 3)
  - Presidential election politics
    - Abortion (Box 4)
    - Voters (Box 4)
    - Democrats
      - General (Box 4)
      - Hubert Humphrey, 1968 candidate (Box 4)
      - Edward Kennedy, 1972 election hopes (Box 4)
      - Robert Kennedy, 1968 candidate (Box 4)
      - Eugene McCarthy, 1968 challenge to Johnson (Box 4)
      - George McGovern, 1972 candidate (Box 4)
      - George Wallace, 1968, 1972 third-party candidate (Box 4)
    - Republicans
      - General (Box 4)
      - Richard Nixon, long-shot candidate (Box 4)
      - Ronald Reagan, recalled to California (Box 4)
      - Nelson Rockefeller, highly financial campaign (Box 4)
      - George Romney, bailed out early (Box 4)
      - George McGovern, 1972 candidate (Box 4)
      - George Wallace, 1968, 1972 third-party candidate (Box 4)
  - Bureaucracy
    - Covert activities, unchecked wiretapping (Box 4)
    - Electoral reform, voting age reduced to 18 (Box 4)
    - J. Edgar Hoover, criticized by Ramsey Clark, Attorney General (Box 4)
    - Postal reform (Box 4)
  - Civil rights
    - Busing (Box 4)
    - Integration and segregation (Box 4)
    - Native Americans, Navajo land claims (Box 4)
    - Women's equality, undermining the U.S. image (Box 4)
  - Crime, growing without restraint (Box 4)
  - Economics
    - Agriculture (Box 5)
    - The consumer (Box 5)
    - Food prices (Box 5)
    - Inflation (Box 5)
    - International (Box 5)
    - Penn Central bankruptcy (Box 5)
    - Taxes (Box 5)
    - U.S. economy, 2 folders (Box 5)
    - Union vs. management, 3 folders (Box 5)
    - Wall Street (Box 5)
    - Welfare and pork-barrel highway bill (Box 5)
  - Environment
    - Energy shortage (Box 5)
    - Highway fatalities (Box 5)
    - Hurricane damage (Box 5)
    - Legislative protection (Box 6)
    - Nuclear weapons (Box 6)
    - Overcrowded parks (Box 6)
    - Trucking industry (Box 6)
  - John Doe, average citizen (Box 6)
  - Medicine
    - Common cold (Box 6)
    - Heart transplant (Box 6)
    - Hong Kong flu (Box 6)
    - Medical costs (Box 6)
    - Untested drugs (Box 6)
  - Space exploration, 2 folders (Box 6)
  - Supersonic transport, Concorde (Box 6)
  - Terrorism and skyjacking (Box 6)
  - Urban plight (Box 6)
  - Vietnam
    - American involvement, 3 folders (Box 6)
    - American involvement, 3 folders (Box 7)
    - Armed forces (Box 7)
    - Cambodia (Box 7)
    - The draft (Box 7)
    - Henry Cabot Lodge (Box 7)
    - My Lai (Box 7)
    - Paris talks, 2 folders (Box 7)
    - Politics (Box 7)
    - U.S.S. Pueblo (Box 7)
  - Weather (Box 7)
  - Youth
    - Academia under fire (Box 7)
    - Anti-war protests (Box 7)
    - Counter-culture (Box 7)
    - Educational system (Box 7)
    - Graduates facing the world (Box 7)
    - Student loans (Box 7)
    - Students for a Democratic Society (Box 7)
  - Miscellaneous (Box 7)